Spider VPN is committed to protecting your privacy. We want you to understand what information we collect, what we don’t collect, and how we collect, use, and store information. We do not collect logs of your activity, including no logging of browsing history, traffic destination, data content, or DNS queries. We also never store connection logs, meaning no logs of your IP address, your outgoing VPN IP address, connection timestamp, or session duration.

Our guiding principle towards data collection is to only collect the minimal data required to operate a world-class VPN service at scale. We designed our systems to not have sensitive data about our customers; even when compelled we cannot provide data that we do not possess.

General Information
-------------------

Spider VPN collects four types of information:

### (i) Information related to your account (“personal information”)

This information is collected for the purpose of administering your Spider VPN subscription, and includes your name, email address, and payment information, which you submit on our order page when you subscribe for the Services. We do not audit or otherwise check the validity of your chosen name or email address, you are free to use whatever name and email address you wish

### (ii) Aggregate Apps and VPN connection summary statistics

Spider VPN collects minimal information about usage In order to maintain excellent customer support and quality of service. The section below describes in detail what specific information we collect. These statistics never include anything about what the user did with the VPN: no data about the contents or destinations of VPN traffic, no DNS queries, and no IP addresses.

### (iii) (User-controlled option): Anonymous VPN connection diagnostics and crash reports

VPN connection diagnostics are anonymized and cannot be tied back to individual Spider VPN users. This feature is similar to a “send bug report” option. Users can specify in the settings menu of any Spider VPN App whether to send these data to us.

Personal Information
--------------------

Spider VPN collects personal information which you provide to us directly through the Site. We require that you provide personal information, such as an email address and payment information, in order to establish an Spider VPN account, and so that we can email you, collect payments from you, and respond to support queries that you initiate. We do not audit or otherwise check the validity of your chosen name or email address, you are free to use whatever name and email address you wish. The specific information collected varies depending on the payment method you choose. To minimize the amount of personal information you submit to us, we recommend that you use bitcoin or crypo currency payments when subscribing to our Service.

With some forms of payment, the Site may redirect you to the website of a third-party payment processor (namely PayPal, BitPay, or Stripe etc to complete the transaction. To understand what personal information these processors collect and store, please refer to the respective processor’s terms and privacy policy.

Spider VPN uses your email address for the following reasons:

To send emails related to payment transactions;

To provide links to our Site, including password reset emails;

To send you updates and announcements;

To communicate with you about your VPN services or respond to your communications;

To send marketing information, such as Spider VPN offers, surveys, invitations, and content about other matters in connection with Spider VPN (“Marketing emails”). You may choose to not receive Marketing emails by following the opt-out procedure described in these emails.

Spider VPN uses your personal information only for the purposes listed in this Privacy Policy, and we do not sell your personal information to third parties.

Aggregate Apps and VPN Connection Summary Statistics
----------------------------------------------------

We ensure that we never log browsing history, traffic destination, data content, IP addresses, or DNS queries. Therefore:

We do not know which user ever accessed a particular website or service.

We do not know which user was connected to the VPN at a specific time or which VPN server IP addresses they used.

We do not know the set of original IP addresses of a user’s computer.

Should anyone try to compel Spider VPN to release user information based on any of the above, we cannot supply this information because the data don’t exist.

In order to maintain excellent customer support and quality of service, Spider VPN collects the following information related to your VPN usage:

### Apps and Apps versions

We collect information related to which Apps and Apps version(s) you have activated. Knowing your current version of the Apps allows our customer support team to troubleshoot technical issues with you.

### Successful connection

We collect information about whether you have successfully established a VPN connection on a particular day (but not a specific time of the day), to which VPN location (but not your assigned outgoing IP address), and from which country/ISP (but not your source IP address). This minimal information assists us in providing technical support, such as identifying connection problems, providing country-specific advice about how to best use our service, and to enable Spider VPN engineers to identify and fix network issues.

### Aggregate sum of data transferred (in MB)

We collect information regarding the total sum of data transfer you consume. Although we provide unlimited data transfer, if we notice that a single user pushes more traffic than thousands of users combined, thereby affecting the quality of service for other Spider VPN users, we may contact them for an explanation.

Storing of Information Related to Email, Live Chat, and Feedback Forms
----------------------------------------------------------------------

Spider VPN keeps records of any correspondence, questions, complaints, or compliments you submit to us through our Site or Services, along with our response. Depending on how you contact Spider VPN, we may collect your email address and any additional information you provide to us. Having full correspondence records enables our staff to provide the best possible customer support experience.

Security Measures to Protect Your Information
---------------------------------------------

Spider VPN uses best-in-class physical, procedural, and technical security with respect to our offices and information storage facilities so as to prevent any loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, or modification of information. Access to user information is restricted to staff who require such access to perform their job functions.

While we believe these systems are robust, it is important to understand that no data security measures in the world can offer 100% protection.

Servers are housed in data centres with strong security practices. None of these data centres centres require us to collect or store any traffic data or personal information related to your use of VPN Services. If any data center were to ask us to log such data, we would immediately cease operations with said data center and find alternative options.

Even if a government were to physically seize one of our VPN servers and manage to break their disk encryption, there would be no logs or information that would tie any individual user to a particular event, website, or behavior.

Cookies
-------

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small text file used to store information about your visit to the Site. Cookies let Spider VPN optimize and improve the user experience of the Site by helping us deliver certain functionalities, such as website login and language settings. The cookies we use may vary over time as we continuously update and improve our Site.

### Disabling cookies

You are free to change your cookie preferences at any time. You can do this in the settings panel for your browser. Depending on which browser and device you use, you may be able to control which cookies you allow, which cookies you want to block in the future, and delete cookies. For more information about these settings, please refer to the “help” section of your browser. Note that Spider VPN’s Site may not work as intended if you choose to disable cookies.

### Spider VPN’s cookies

The cookies set by Spider VPN enable us to set your language preference, attribute visitors to a marketing channel, and, once you log in, securely show you information that is specific to your account. The cookies contain a user identifier, but no directly personally identifying information such as your name or email address, and do not track any activity outside of Spider VPN’s domains.

Third-party Websites
--------------------

The Site may contain links to external websites that do not fall under Spider VPN’s domain. Spider VPN is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such external websites.

Consent and Age Restrictions
----------------------------

By using the Site, Content, Apps, Software, or Services, you agree to have your information handled as described in our [Terms of Service](https://www.expressvpn.com/tos) and Privacy Policy.

The Services are intended for adults aged 18 and above. If you believe your child has provided information to us, please let us know immediately.

Changes to the Privacy Policy
-----------------------------

We may change our Privacy Policy from time to time, without prior notice to you, consistent with applicable privacy laws and principles. Your continued use of the Site or Services constitutes your acceptance of our Privacy Policy.
